莱纳德
Leonard...
我有个天大的坏消息
I've got terrible news.
怎么了
What's going on?
在我说之前  或许需要给你点心里缓冲
Before I tell you, perhaps I should soften the blow.
你的脸对称得很讨喜
You're face is pleasingly symmetrical.
你就说吧
Just tell me.
一个瑞典的物理学家团队
A Swedish team of physicists
想要抢先一步进行我们的超流体漩涡实验
is trying to scoop our super-fluid vortex experiment.
好吧  这是有点恶心
Oh, well, that kind of stinks.
什么叫"有点恶心"
"That kind of stinks"?
你应该要更不爽啊
Why aren't you more upset?
我刚才给你缓冲太多了吗
Did I soften the blow too much?
因为这副尊容更像是一幅毕加索的抽象画
Because this here is more like a Picasso painting.
那我们要怎么办
What are we going to do?
立刻进行实验
Perform the experiment immediately.
我也想  但我们需要液氦
I'd love to, but we need liquid helium
而我们订的氦要晚一个月才到
and our shipment's on back order for a month.
什么  一个月  你跟我闹呢
A month? What? Are you kidding me?
现在就很适合你给我做心里缓冲啊
That would have been a good time for you to soften the blow.
这T恤能衬托出你那深邃的蓝眸
That shirt brings out the blue in your eyes.
谢谢  你嘴真甜
Thank you. Aren't you sweet.
我们去查查大学里
Let's go check to see if the university
还有没有氦气存货吧
has any helium in reserve.
你知道我今天差点就不穿这件衣服吗
Did you know that I almost didn't wear this shirt today?
巴里  我们碰到了麻烦
Hey, Barry, we're in trouble.
我们需要液氦
We need liquid helium--
系里有多余的可以让我们用吗
does the department have any we can use?
抱歉  这东西有些短缺
Sorry, there's a shortage.
而仅有的存货  我要拿来做量子激发研究
And what we do have I need for my quantum excitation study.
你那个实验不需要用多少啊
But you won't need much for that.
的确  但如果成功了
True, but if it's successful,
我开派对要拿来灌气球啊
I'm having a party with balloons.
别这样  巴里  有个瑞典团队
Come on, Barry, there's a Swedish team
想抢先进行我们的实验
trying to run our experiment before us.
你真不能匀一点给我们吗
Can't you spare any?
你们老实说  如果今天换我碰到这情况
Be honest-- if the shoe was on the other foot,
你们会愿意帮我吗
would you do this for me?
-会  -不可能
- Yes. - No chance.
你帮倒忙呢
What are you doing?
他说老实说  所以我老实说啊
He said be honest, so I was honest.
你母亲没教你吗  诚实为上
Didn't your mother tell you? It's the best policy.
所以你意下如何
So, what do you say?
下辈子吧
Hell no.
他可以给我们点缓冲再说的
He could've softened the blow.
翻译：爱搞笑钱德勒赛  强迫症莫妮卡猫
猫中之王  别扭大菜
你们为啥需要找他要氦气
Why do you need Kripke?
你们不能直接去派对用品店买点吗
Can't you just go to Party City for helium?
我们得跑遍它们全加州的店才够
We'd have to go to every Party City in California.
听起来就像5月5日节时的你啊
Sounds like you on Cinco de Mayo.
墨西哥节日  庆祝某场战役的胜利
在节日当日会有各种派对  舞蹈等等
我办的那个派对到5月7日
Hey, people were still talking about that party
还有人赞不绝口呢
on siete de Mayo.
莱纳德  如果那个瑞典团队赢了我们
Leonard, if that Swedish team beats us,
我此生都再也不愿享用那个国家的东西了
I will never be able to enjoy anything from their country again.
那真挺可惜的  因为瑞典的肉丸
Which is a shame, because Swedish meatballs
是我最爱的用牙签插着吃的肉丸
are my favorite toothpick-delivered meatball.
如果你们真迫切需要液氦  我认识个人
If you need liquid helium so bad, I know a guy
他能帮你们搞到  前提是不许问太多问题
who can get you some, if you don't ask too many questions.
-他是何方神圣  -他在哪儿工作
- Who is he? - Where does he work?
他怎么能搞到氦
How does he get the helium?
问多少问题才算是太多问题
How many questions are too many questions?
或许他不适合你们
Maybe he's not for you.
四题  答案是四题
Four questions. There answer's four.
你知道之前谁晚上去约会了吗
Hey, you know who went out on a date the other night?
斯图尔特
Stuart.
那恭喜他啊
Oh, good for him.
我也这么觉得
I thought so, too.
所以这妞是无家可归还是要栽赃陷害他
So is she, like, homeless, or framing him for a crime?
他在手机上装了一个约会软件
He's using some kind of dating app on his phone.
叫什么
Oh, which one?
或许我们能让艾米也试试
Maybe we can get Amy to try it.
不知道
I don't know.
斯图尔特  你能过来一下吗
Stuart, can you come in here?
他试着跟我解释过
He tried to explain it to me.
上面会显示出附近的用户
It shows you pictures of people nearby,
你能左右滑动换人看  看起来像个游戏
you swipe them around, it looks kind of like a game.
如果你游戏输了  你就得跟斯图尔特约会
Oh, and if you lose the game, you have to go out with Stuart.
找我干嘛
What's up?
你能给我们看看那个约会软件吗
Can you show us that dating app?
可以啊  行
Oh, yeah, sure.
这软件真是改变了我的人生
This thing has changed my life.
所以你约到了几个姑娘
Wow. So how many girls have you met?
2个
Two.
我想我不用多说
I probably don't need to mention
2跟0之间相隔了"1"个世界吧
there's an entire number between that and zero.
这软件怎么用
Well, so how does it work?
上面会显示出
Uh, well, it-it shows me all
方圆八公里内所有使用这软件的
the single women in a five-mile radius
单身女子
who are using the app.
如果我喜欢她们的长相  那就点"赞"
If I like the way they look, I hit "Thumbs up."
如果不喜欢  就点"烂"
If I don't, "Thumbs down."
那怎么样的情况会让你给姑娘点"烂"呢
Oh, what would make you give a girl a thumbs down?
首次发生时  我会告诉你
First time it happens I will let you know.
我收到那个氦气男的回信了
Oh, hey. I just heard back from the liquid helium guy.
他怎么说
What's he say?
他有我们要的东西  可以今晚交易
He's got what we need and can meet us tonight.
是吗
Oh, really?
你知道我不喜欢晚上买东西
You know I don't like buying things at night.
2009年1月7日
January 7, 2009.
我晚上11点半去买
I went to the Ralph's at 11:30pm to pick up
隔天早餐要吃的燕麦片  然后我看到了啥
Cracklin' Oat Bran for the morning and what did I see?
在给早餐谷物架补货的店员
The man restocking the cereal shelves.
没错  他干嘛了
That's right. And what did he do?
他直接把早餐片递给了你  然后叫你瘦竹竿
He handed you the box directly and called you Stretch.
伤心往事历历在目啊
It's like it was yesterday.
那你到底还想不想要液氦了
Do you want liquid helium or not?
我当然想要啊
Of course I do.
我不想被那个瑞典团队捷足先登
I don't want that Swedish team scooping us.
那我告诉他我们同意
Then I'm going to tell him we're in.
莱纳德  等等  这非常不道德
Leonard, wait. This is highly unethical.
我们只是稍微变通一下
We're just bending the rules a little.
我们有进行实验的拨款
We have grant money to do the experiment,
所以我们拿这款项去买实验需要的氦
so we're going to spend it on the helium we need.
这又不像戈德法布博士
It's not like when Dr. Goldfarb
对外声称自己买了一个电子显微镜
claimed he bought an electron microscope
而真相是他在
and he was really just keeping
在加州范奈司的金屋藏"金丝猫"
a Russian girl in an apartment in Van Nuys.
那女孩帮他做研究吗
Was she helping him with his research?
"当然"
Sure.
我们到底要不要买
So, are we doing this?
好吧  可他的氦是从哪里弄来的
Okay, but where does he get the helium?
还记得吗  不许多问
Remember? Don't ask too many questions?
但这有违我们大学的校规
Uh, but this is violating university code.
稍微有点  但...
A little, but...
爱因斯坦曾说过
if I may quote Einstein,
"追求科学需要我们
"The pursuit of science calls us
抛开一切规章制度"
to ignore the rules set by man."
好吧  买吧
All right, do it.
告诉他我们同意见面
Tell him we're in.
好了
Done.
我在网上查不到爱因斯坦那句话
I can't find that quote on the Internet.
是不是你瞎编的
Did you make that up?
在回答之前
Before I answer,
我得先说  你的皮肤也太好了吧
may I just say your skin has never looked better.
你的嘴呀  跟抹了蜜一样
Aren't you just made of sugar.
我不确定对此该作何感想
I'm not sure how I feel about this.
放心  就让他把软件装你手机上吧
Oh, come on, just let him put the app on your phone.
对啊  斯尔图特约到了两个妞呢
Yeah, Stuart got two dates with it.
其中一个要没拒绝我  早发展到床上了
One of which would've ended in sex had she not said no.
好了  装好了
Okay, all set.
让我看看
Okay, let me see.
不行  不行
Nope, nope,
不行
nope...
这个帅气
Oh, he's cute!
泪滴图案的纹身
Doesn't a teardrop tattoo
不是代表他曾杀过人吗
mean he murdered someone?
他对此感到痛心啊
And he's sad about it.
我以为你很晚才会回来呢
Hey, I thought you were gonna be out late?
如果你想让我晚点回家
If you wanted me to stay out later,
就应该给我多点零花钱啊
you should've given me more spending money.
你们在干什么
What are you guys up to?
我们帮艾米注册了约会软件
We put Amy on a dating app,
现在在看上面都有什么人
and we're seeing what's out there.
有意思  让我看看
Oh, fun! Let me see.
不行
Uh, no...
不行  绝对不行
no, uh, definitely not.
这人哪里不好了
What was wrong with that guy?
他是印度人
Uh, he's Indian.
我们已经有一个阿三哥了
We've already got one of those.
我们应该找一个拉丁帅哥
Ooh, we should find a nice Latino.
让我们这个小团体更完美
It really round us out.
我想试试
Hey, I want to try.
不好意思  能把手机还给我吗
Uh, excuse me, c-can I have my phone back?
等等  我在帮你寻找下一位挚爱呢
Hang on, I'm trying to find you the next great love of your life.
你未来孩子的父亲
The man who will father your children.
好了  脏辫雷鬼头的白人怎么样
Okay, yes or no on white guy with dreadlocks?
那一定是他
That must be him.
肯定啦
Oh, of course.
一辆没有标识的全白面包车
An nondescript, white panel van.
以下这句话你可能会听着耳熟
You may be familiar with it from the sentence:
"他们的尸体
"Their bodies were found
是在一辆没有标识的全白面包车内找到"
in a nondescript, white panel van."
你们好
What's up?
我是莱纳德
Uh, I'm Leonard.
-这位是我的朋友  -叫我兽主甘
- This is my friend-- - I'm Skippy.
兽主甘·卡瓦诺
Skippy Cavanaugh.
好
Great.
钱带来了吗
You got the cash?
带来了  在这里呢
Uh, yeah, uh, right here.
等等  且慢且慢
Wait, hold on, hold on.
我们怎么知道
How do we know that you're not gonna
你不会拿了钱就跑
take the money and drive away?
你这是干嘛  兽主甘
What ya doing, Skippy?
这是跟70年代的罪案连续剧学的
Exactly what 1970s television crime dramas have taught us.
你先把氦给我们
You give us the helium first.
我怎么知道你们会不会收了货
Oh, how do I know you're not gonna
不给钱就跑啊
drive away without paying me?
看来我不是唯一一个
Guess I'm not the only one
会看70年代罪案连续剧的人
who watches '70s television crime dramas.
听着  你可以信任我们
Look, you can trust us.
我们是受人尊敬的科学家
We're respected scientists.
他是
Well, he is.
我是一名婚礼策划师
I'm a wedding planner,
然而自己却找不到真爱
who can't find love himself.
虽然很讽刺  但重点是
It's ironic, but the point is
我们无法信任你
we can't trust you.
你只是个在停车场的鬼祟男
You're a sketchy character in a parking garage.
没错  在我看来
Yeah, well, from my perspective,
你们俩也是鬼祟男
that's how you two appear to me.
我从未这样想过
Well, I never thought of it like that.
天啊  参照系让人措手不及
Boy, frame of reference will just sneak up on you, won't it?
我朋友对钱的担心不无道理
My friend does make a decent point about the money.
我也觉得先给钱不妥
I don't feel comfortable just handing it over up front.
不给钱  不给氦
Ah-ah-ah, no money, no helium.
看来我们陷入了"逼和"的局面
Seems we're at a, uh, stalemate.
严格来说不算
Not technically.
在国际象棋中  "逼和"指的局面是
In chess, a stalemate refers to a situation
无棋可动  无路可走
in which there are no remaining moves.
你还有很多条路可以选
Uh, you have plenty of moves available.
你可以揍扁我们  然后把钱拿走
You could beat us up and steal the money.
你也可以杀了我们
You could kill us, you know.
你只是被自己的想象力限制了
Really, you're only limited by your imagination.
这么多年来  虽然我嘴上说"逼和"
All these years, I've been using "stalemate,"
但我真正要表达的是"僵局"
when I really mean "impasse."
我感觉自己好傻
I feel foolish.
这都不重要  不管这是"逼和"
I don't think it matters if this is a stalemate
"僵局"或是"墨西哥对峙"
or an impasse or a Mexican standoff.
意为对峙多方为了个人利益而不愿放下武器
率先让步的局面
我们现在应该怎么办
What are we gonna do here?
等等  这怎么能算"墨西哥对峙"呢
Oh, whoa, whoa, how can it be a Mexican standoff?
谁都知道这种情况得有三方对峙
Everybody knows you need three sides for that.
不一定
Not necessarily.
很多人争论"墨西哥对峙"的本质在于
Uh, many argue the essence of a Mexican standoff
就是没人能够全身而退
is that no one can walk away from the conflict
却毫发无伤
without incurring harm.
我没听明白
Hmm, I don't follow.
我给你举个例子吧
Let me give you an example.
今天早些时候
Earlier today,
我破解了你电邮的标头隐藏资讯
I decoded the headers on your e-mail,
我知道你的名字叫肯尼斯·菲兹杰拉德
and I know that your name is Kenneth Fitzgerald.
然后我找出了你的住址和工作地点
From that, I figured out where you live and where you work.
现在  要把情况变成"墨西哥对峙"
Now, to make this a Mexican standoff,
我会说些类似这样的话
I would say something like, uh,
"给我氦气  不然我就去当局告发你"
"You give us the helium or I'll turn you in to the authorities."
你这是在威胁我吗
Is that a threat?
没错  看  你开始懂了嘛
Yeah, exactly. See, you're getting it.
好呀  我也知道你们在哪里工作
Yeah, well, I know where you work, all right?
如果你们想整我  我就举报你
And if you mess with me, I'll report you,
然后我会把你俩揍得亲娘都认不出
then I'll pound your asses into the ground.
太棒了  现在这才叫"墨西哥对峙"
Perfect! Now we really are in a Mexican standoff.
是不是又到了那种
Is this one of those times
我赢了战役  却输了战争的局面
where I've won the battle but lost the war?
恐怕是哦  兽主甘
Afraid so, Skippy.
我就说咱们不该晚上出来买东西
I told you we shouldn't go shopping at night.
好了  大家都冷静一下
All right, let's all just calm down.
谁都不想举报谁
Nobody wants to report anybody.
我不喜欢跟你们做买卖  我要走了
No, I don't like this. I'm out.
别别  等一下  不要走
No, no, no. Wait, don't go.
请听我解释
Just let me explain.
我们是物理学家  我们只是想证明
We're physicists, and we're trying to prove a hypothesis
一个我们研究了一年的假设而已
that we've been working on for over a year.
真的吗  什么假设
Really? What's the hypothesis?
时空可以用
Space-time can be interpreted as
一个N维超流体的表面来解释
the surface of an n-dimensional superfluid.
有可能哦  有可能
Could be, could be.
说下去
Go on.
现在有一个瑞典团队读了我们的论文
Okay, but now there's this Swedish team that read our paper
想抢先我们一步获得实验成果
and they're trying to beat us to our own discovery.
所以我们真的很需要这罐氦气
We really need this helium.
抱歉我之前撒谎
And I'm sorry I lied about
说我自己是没人爱的婚礼策划师
being a wedding planner who can't find love.
不过我现在的确是单身  你有人可以介绍给我吗
Although I am currently single, if you know anybody.
钱给你  买卖能继续吗
Here's the money. Can we do this?
好吧
Okay.
那些占你们便宜的科学家实在太不要脸了
It's a shame about those scientists ripping you off.
我还以为瑞典的朋友们
I expected a higher ethical standard
道德标准会更高呢
from our friends in Sweden.
这事在我们学术界其实挺常见的
It's actually pretty common in our field.
我们也拿他们没办法
Not much you can do about it.
如果你们出的价够高
Well, for the right amount of money,
又知道他们的住址
if you know where they live,
我倒是知道好多种对付他们的"办法"
there's, uh, plenty we could do about it.
听到了吗  莱纳德
Did you hear that, Leonard?
我们有好多种对付他们的办法呢
There's plenty we could do about it.
你有名片吗
Do you have a card?
好了  出来啦
Okay, here we go.
现在大家都能看到了
Now everyone can see.
好的
All right.
大家觉得斗鸡眼麦克如何啊
Where do we stand on cross-eyed Mike?
好歹他不能乱瞟看别的姑娘了
You know he won't be looking at other girls.
除非她们坐在他鼻头上
Unless they're sitting on the end of his nose.
好  好  好   按"烂"
Okay, okay, okay. Thumbs down.
下一个
Next.
看看他那一嘴小牙齿
Ew, check out his tiny teeth.
他好像一只人形海豚
He looks like a man-dolphin.
如果他床技超群  你可以丢一条小鱼作奖励
Wait, if he's good in bed, she can throw him a fish.
我爱你  艾米
I love you, Amy.
我开始有罪恶感了
Okay, I'm starting to feel guilty.
我们是不是太毒舌了啊
Aren't we being a little mean?
你说得对
That's a fair point.
我们肯定不会当着本人的面这么取笑他
We wouldn't make fun of someone like this to their face.
看  是斯图尔特
Look, it's Stuart!
你最好回避一下吧
You may want to leave the room.
这边请  哈维叔叔
Right this way, Uncle Harvey.
你能不能别装了
Will you stop with that already?
我这是在避免引人注意
I'm trying not to attract attention.
你让他向清洁女工脱帽致意还不够引人注意吗
And tipping his hat to the cleaning lady didn't do that?
她说了"晚安"[西语]  我叔叔还能怎么做
She said, "Buenas noches." What was he supposed to do?
我们还是赶紧开始实验吧
Let's just start the experiment.
莱纳德  我们应该把故事编圆了
Leonard, we should probably have our story straight
以防到时被抓住
in case we get caught.
我们不会被抓的
We're not getting caught.
你又不能保证这一点
Well, you can't be sure of that.
万一卖氦气的人出卖我们呢
What if the helium dealer rats us out?
万一克里普奇问起这氦气的来历呢
What if Kripke asks where we got it?
万一学校查了我的家谱
What if the university checks my family tree
发现我根本就没有一个哈维叔叔怎么办
and finds out I don't have an Uncle Harvey?
卖家没这么无聊  克里普奇又管不着我们
The dealer doesn't care, Kripke has no authority over us,
而你和金属罐子有亲属关系
and you being related to a metal container
反而更能解释你的种种
would explain a lot.
帮我把它接起来
Help me hook this up.
怎么了
What?
-你看到这个贴纸了吗   -怎么了
- Well, did you see this sticker? - What is it?
虽然掉了一大半  不过剩下部分还依稀可见
It's partially torn off, but the segment that remains reads:
专属财产和一个U字
"Property of" and the letter "U."
可能是南加大  或加州大学洛杉矶分校吧
It's probably USC or UCLA.
但万一指的是美国[U.S.]政府专属财产怎么办
Yeah, but what if it's "Property of U.S. Government"?
德州的阿马里洛就有一个国家氦气保护区
There's a national helium reserve in Amarillo, Texas.
如果这个是从那里偷的
If this was stolen from there,
我们就犯下了联邦重罪
we're accessories to a federal crime.
别这么快就下结论
Let's not jump to conclusions.
U可以指好多东西呢
A lot of things start with "U."
你说得对
That's true.
可以指美国空军
There's the U.S. Air Force,
美国国防部  美国海军
U.S. Department of Defense, U.S. Navy,
还可以指你和我一起吃牢饭
"You" And I are going to jail.
听着  我们可以按计划做完实验
Listen, we can do the experiment as planned
让瑞典人哭着回家找妈妈
and beat the Swedish team to the punch,
或者我们可以和科研梦吻别
or we can kiss our dreams good-bye
因为我们不敢违反一点小规则
because we were to afraid to break a few rules.
女士您好
Ma'am.
好了  大家都记住规则了吗
Okay, does everyone remember the rules?
如果他没穿衣服  喝一口
If he's shirtless, one sip.
带着宠物摆姿势  喝两口
Posing with a pet, two sips.
带宠物又没穿衣服  猛灌
Pet and shirtless, chug like it's your job.
开始
And pull!
这条内裤我也有
I have that same underwear!
灌
Chug!
艾米  你收到条短信
Mm, Amy, you're getting a text.
给我
Oh, um, give me that.
"昨晚玩得很愉快"
"I had a great time last night."
停停停  都别看了
No, no, st-stop reading that.
-谁是戴夫  -我...
- Who's Dave?  - I...
你昨晚上去约会了
You went on a date last night?
你在跟谁交往吗
Are you seeing someone?
没有  不是那样的
No, it-it's not like that.
"我很乐意再约你出来玩"
"And I'd love to take you out again"?
-艾米  -什么
- Amy! - What?
-难以置信啊  -我的神啊
- Can't believe it. - Oh, my God.
好吧  就是那样
Okay, it's like that.
感谢你能回来
Thank you for coming back.
没事  通常情况下我不会的
Yeah, well, normally I wouldn't,
可我女儿跟她的朋友们今晚在我家住
but my daughter's having a sleepover, and there's only
尖叫加水果姐姐已经超越我的承受极限了
so much screaming and Katy Perry a man can take.
美国知名女歌手  歌曲大多唱女性自强自尊
颇受小女孩到青少年女性喜欢
总之把钱还给我们
Anyway, if you could just give us our money back,
你拿走你的氦气  我们马上走
you can have your helium and we'll be on our way.
好  它有什么问题吗
Yeah, well, is there something wrong with it?
没有  我们只是改变主意了
No, nothing. We just changed our mind.
他是四眼田鸡  我是自以为是的瘦竹竿
He has glasses and I'm a know-it-all;
我俩不适合蹲监狱
we are not built for prison.
也是  有道理
Yeah, I hear you.
你们俩是好人  所以我...
Well, you're good guys, so I'll, uh...
我会把氦气拿走
I'll take the helium off your hands.
谢谢你
Thank you.
但是钱不能还给你们
But you ain't getting your money back.
你是想占我俩便宜吗
You're taking advantage of us?
我们不是一起弄清过语义吗
We clarified nomenclature together.
虽然我跟普通人一样都爱听语义教学
Look, I enjoy semantic digressions as much as the next guy,
可是在商言商嘛
but, uh, this is business.
算了
You know what?
就这样吧  钱你留着
It's fine. Keep the money.
我们只想赶紧脱手
We just want to be done with this.
没问题  但我得跟你们收点
No problem, but I am gonna have to charge you
氦气退货费
a small helium restocking fee.
我不懂了
I don't understand.
他想再要钱
He wants more money.
那最好别超过一千美金
Well, it better not be more than a thousand dollars;
我身上就这么多了
that's all I've got on me.
正好就是那数
That's exactly how much it is.
终于
Finally,
有个顺利的事了
something breaks our way.
不敢相信你居然在跟人约会
I can't believe you're seeing someone
而我们什么都不知道
and we don't even know about it.
对  你为什么不告诉我们呢
Yeah, why wouldn't you tell us?
因为这事才开始  又很奇怪
Because it's new and weird
我自己还在摸索阶段
and I'm just trying to figure it all out.
而且我知道  如果告诉了你们
And I knew if I told you guys
我已经跟几个人约过会了
I had been out with a few people
你们肯定会表现得太过兴奋
that you'd get way too excited about it.
还几个人
A few people?
-什么  -艾米
- What?! - Amy!
所以我们能问问  进展如何吗
So, are we allowed to ask how it's going?
还行
It's going fine.
基本就是跟人见面喝个咖啡
It's mostly just been meeting people for coffee.
什么
Wha...?!
我以为我们每次都要...
I thought we were all...
当我没说
Never mind.
我以为你还没准备好跟别人约会呢
I-I thought you weren't ready to start seeing people.
我没什么约会经验
Well, I don't have much experience dating,
所以觉得多出去见见世面
so I decided it would be good for me
对我来说是好事
to, you know, get out there a little.
挺好的
Well, good for you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你已经约过几个人了
And how many guys have you gone out with?
拜托不要超过2个
Please be less than two.
-3个  -靠
- Three. - Damn it.
虽然我们可能会被瑞典人打败
Well, the Swedes might beat us,
可起码不用在监狱里被人"头皮转转功"
but at least we won't get gang-noogied in prison.
监狱电影你是只看过《监狱宝贝蛋》吗
Is Ernest Goes to Jail the only prison movie you've seen?
那电影把宝宝我吓乖了  莱纳德
It scared me straight, Leonard.
我想了想
Hey, I've been thinking.
是我太小气了
I was being petty.
你们可以用我的氦气
You can have my helium.
谢谢你  巴里
Thank you, Barry.
但你们的论文得加上我的名字
But you have to add my name to your paper.
太荒谬了
That's preposterous.
我觉得挺公平的
I don't know, seems fair.
没我你们也做不成实验
You can't do it without me.
给我们一分钟
Can you give us a minute?
慢慢商量
Take your time.
为了做效果  我会慢慢倒退出去
I'll walk out backwards for dramatic effect.
我不喜欢这样被敲诈
I don't like being extorted like this.
尤其还是被他
Especially by him of all people.
我也不喜欢  可我们别无选择
Me neither, but what other choice do we have?
我保证这是最后一次
I promise this is the last time.
维基百科上写着呢
It's says right here on the Wikipedia
"墨西哥对峙是由至少三方
"A Mexican standoff is a confrontation between
相对而立的结果"
at least three parties."
你怎么敢信维基百科
How can you trust Wikipedia
他们居然用"相对而立"形容三方
if they use "between" to refer to three parties?
它们应该用三足鼎立  对不对
They should've used "among," right?
或者鼎分三足  如果他们想带点古风古韵
Or "amongst," if they were feeling whimsically archaic.
好了  别聊这些闲话了
All right, enough with the chitchat.
我们到底还看不看《监狱宝贝蛋》了
Are we gonna watch Ernest Goes to Jail or not?
当然了
Absolutely.
但如果这部片子把你吓到从此老实做人
But don't be surprised if this movie sets you
你可别太吃惊
on the straight and narrow.
我这人乐于改变
I am open to change.